A Guide to the Warren Morton Washington Papers WW2008.001
National Center for Atmospheric Science Library Special Collections
- Diversity Activites, 1963 - Present; 4.0 linear ft. (1 box) Box 4, Black Environmental Science Trustr (BEST) - 9 folders Box 16, Amercian Academy for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) - 12 folders Box 35 UCAR/NCAR Correnspondence - 8 folders, 1 blue binder; Warren M. Washington, Ph.D., Senior Scie
  - 1966 - 1980, AAAS; 16.0 linear ft. (1 box) Folder 1 - Committee on Minorities in Science General Correspondence (1 - 3)) Folder 2 - Committee on Opportunities in Science Folder 3 - Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 Folder 4 - Committee on Opportunities in Science Meet
    - Correspondence Committee on Opportunities in Science and Panels; Board Meeting and resolutions; Brown, Janet W.; Mead, Margaret, Revelle, Roger; 8/05/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (1) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Revisions to Resolution on Native American Science and Medicine; 6/23/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (1) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - AAAS Committee On Opportunities In Science, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (1) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence Brown, Janet, W.; Science Magazine: Report of meeting with Ormes, Robert, Managing Editor of Science; 7/31/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (1) (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Travel Expense voucher for trips to New York, Washington D. C., Kenya; 1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Brown, Janet W., Posner, Susan E.; committee concerns; 1/16/1975, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Prefatory Statement to Accompany Resolution on Native American Science to AAAS Council; 1/29/1975, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Minutes of Committee on Council Affairs meeting 12/08/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Report for the 1974 of the Committee on Opportunities in Science to the AAAS Council, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Hicks, Leslie H.; Science and AAAS; 12/10/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Brown, Janet W.; bibliography of Science Education Programs for Minority Students; 1/29/1975, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - AAAS announces 1975-1976 Congressional Science Fellow Program, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Brown, Janet, W.; Science Magazine and "open" advertisement of South Africa; 12/19/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Preliminary Proposal: Evaluation of Science Education Programs for Minority Students; 11/27/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Brown, Janet, W.; unfinished business Native American Science Resolution; 9/30/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Brown, Janet, W.; Hearings of the Special Sub-committee on Education on Civil rights compliance and Eligibility for Federal Assistance by Institutions of Higher Education; 9/12/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Richmond, Jonas, E.; Hunger and famine in Sahel; 8/12/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Famous Negro Personalities (n.d.), Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Gillmor, C. Stewart; Committee on the Status of Minorities for the History of Science Society; 7/09/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Report of Committee on Opportunities in Science Third Meeting; 2/23-24/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Daddario, Emilio, Q.; Haskins, Caryl; Mead, Margaret; Motivating Minority and Women High School Students in Science and Mathematics; Native American Science and Medicine; 6/18/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Abelson, Philip H.; 5/23/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Microfiche: the Role of the American Negro in the Fields of Science, Final Report, Haber, Louis; Pub Date 9/1966, Committee on Opportunities in Science Meeting Nov 17-18, 1974 (2) (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - AAAS Annual Meeting: Symposium of Special Interest to Minorities and Women; 2/25-3/1/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science meeting; 2/23-24/1974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Preliminary Agenda: Meeting of the Committee on Opportunities in Science; 2/23-24/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science meeting; 2/23-24/1974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence Posner, Susan; COOS Meeting in San Francisco; 2/23-24/1974, Committee on Opportunities in Science meeting; 2/23-24/1974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - AAAS Native Americans Science Meeting; Summary of Meeting and Recommendations; 5/20/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Article The Science Teacher" The Federal Role in Science Education: What’s Inside NSF's Proposed Budget?"; 5/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - AAAS Brochure (n.d.), Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Agenda Meeting for Committee on Opportunities in Science; 6/3-4/1977, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976; Handwritten Notes (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Three year program plan for the Office of Opportunities in Science prepared buy OOS staff; 6/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976; Handwritten Notes (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Report of the year 1976 to the AAAS Council from the Committee on Opportunities in Science, CommiCommittee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Articles and editorials re: dispute over election of Jensen, Arthur R. as fellow of AAAS, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Article Science; AAAS President-Elect, Report of Association, Fellowship members, Officers, staff, committees and representatives for 1977; (Vol. 196), 4/15/1977, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Minutes of the meeting Committee on Opportunities in Science; 5/27-28/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Article Science "AAAS News:AAAS Initiates Barrier-Free Meetings"; (Vol. 192);6/04/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Summary of activities since Committee of Office of Opportunities in Science (COOS) Meeting; 10/02-03/1975, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Tentative Agenda for AAAS Meeting with Puerto Rican Scientists; 5/11/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976; Handwritten Notes (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Elementary and Secondary Science Education (n.d.), Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence Malcom, Shirley Mahaley; Minority Women in Science, Agenda #2; double and trip binds; 5/26/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and articles re: Handicapped Scientists; 5/05/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Testimony for the Senate Subcommittee on the National Science Foundation Budget; 3/03/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - List of Minority Scientific Professional Associations; 5/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - AAAS: Science for Handicapped Students in Higher Educatio; Brown, Janet Welsh; Davis, Cherly Arlene, Redded, Martha Ross; 1978, Booklets (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - AAAS: Handbook; Officers, Organization, Activities; 1978, Booklets (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Articles, three year plan summaries re: AAAS Project on Native Amercians in Science; 1976-1977, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - The Participation of Women in Scientific Research: A study by AAAS supported by the NSF; Participation Rates and Employment Statistics; 1976-1977, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Project on the Handicapped in Science; 7/01/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Recommendations for the Improvement of Science and Mathematics Education for American Indians; Brown, Janet W.; Green, Rayna; 12/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Announcement nominations sought for Membership of National Science Board; NSF Bulletin (Vol. 4, No. 9); 5/1977, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Article Science "1976 AAAS Election Results" (Vol. 194); 12/03/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1977; Handwritten Notes (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - AAAS Annual Meeting 2/12-17/1978; Listing of Symposia, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence Bierly, Eugene W.; 3/23/1976, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence Malcom, Shirley; 10/06/1980, Committee On Opportunity in Science: Correspondence 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - AAAS Regional Energy Seminar Series: Energy and Northwest Indian Lands; 11/13-14/1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Highlights from the Office of Opportuniites in Science; Brown, Janet W.; Carey, William D.; 9/06/1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence; 10/09/1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence Brown, Janet W.; 5/11/1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correpondence Savage, I., Richard; 4/17/1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence Hall, P. Quick; 3/21/1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Report and Recommendations; Conference on Mathematics in American Indian Education; Green, Rayna; Brown, Janet W.; 2/1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence Brown, Janet W.; Carey, William, D.; 11/21/1978-2/20/1979 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Correpondence Carey, William; 12/18/1979, Minority Caucus 1977 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Report of the year 1977 to the AAAS Council from the Committee on Opportunities in Science, Minority Caucus 1977; Handwritten Notes (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Washington, Warren A.; (n.d.), Minority Caucus 1977; Handwritten Notes (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence Brown, Janet W.; Washington, Warren A.; COOS Meeting, Highlights, Summary; 12/21/1977, Minority Caucus 1977 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Conference of Science and Mathematics Faculity and/or Administrators of Predominately Native American Colleges; 5/1977, Minority Caucus 1977 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence Fein, Jay S.; 8/03/1979, Handwritten Notes (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence Minority Caucus meeting; 1/25/1978 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence Dressler, M. Dawn; AAAS Women's Caucus; 2/06/1978 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - AAAS Committee on Opportunities in Science 1977 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - AAAS Board of Directors; 1977, Handwritten Notes (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Report of the year 1977 to the AAAS Council from the Committee on Opportunities in Science, Handwritten notes (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - AAAS Annual Meeting: Meetings and Symposia of special interest to Women, Minority and Handicapped Scientists; 1/12-17/1978 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - UCAR/NCAR Correspondence, Bulk, 1972-1994; 1972-1994; UCATR/NCAR; 35.0 linear ft. (1 box) Folder 1 - Minority recruitment (1 of 2), 1972-1994 Folder 2 - Minority recruitment cont'd Folder 3 - UCAR Affirmative Action records (RESTRICTED) Folder 4 - AMS: Minority scholarships - 1990's Folder 5 - (Box 35)
    - Minority recruitment (1 of 2), 1972-1994, Bulk, 1972-1994; UCAR/NCAR; 1.0 folder (1of 2) (Box 35)
    - Minority recruitment (2 of 2), Bulk, 1972-1994; 1972-1994; UCAR/NCAR; 2.0 folder (2 of 2) (Box 35)
    - UCAR Affirmative Action records, Bulk, 1960-2007; 1960-2007; UCAR/NCAR; 3.0 folder (Box 35)